<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Configuration on ssham: Secure Shell Access Manager</title><link>https://ssham.pacoorozco.info/using-ssham/configuration/</link><description>Recent content in Configuration on ssham: Secure Shell Access Manager</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ssham.pacoorozco.info/using-ssham/configuration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SSH settings</title><link>https://ssham.pacoorozco.info/using-ssham/configuration/ssh-settings/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssham.pacoorozco.info/using-ssham/configuration/ssh-settings/</guid><description>Under this section you can configure how the bastion host will communicate with the rest of remote servers.
Bastion host credentials Private key SSHAM will use this key in order to connect to the remote hosts.
Public key Remote hosts will identify SSHAM with this key. This key should be distributed to the remote hosts to allow access without password.
The key distribution could be done using several approaches: ansible, puppet&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Application defaults</title><link>https://ssham.pacoorozco.info/using-ssham/configuration/app-defaults/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssham.pacoorozco.info/using-ssham/configuration/app-defaults/</guid><description>Remote paths Updater script remote path Path on remote hosts where the ssham-remote-updater.sh will be copied.
authorized_keys remote path Path of the authorized_keys file which contains the SSH keys that can be used for logging into the remote hosts.
SSH remote port Default port to reach remote hosts by SSH protocol.</description></item><item><title>Hybrid configuration</title><link>https://ssham.pacoorozco.info/using-ssham/configuration/hybrid-configuration/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssham.pacoorozco.info/using-ssham/configuration/hybrid-configuration/</guid><description>Hybrid mode If hybrid mode is enabled, the remote hosts will accept other access keys non-managed by SSHAM.
File to keep the managed keys File on remote hosts where SSHAM will generate the managed access keys.
File containing keys non-managed by SSHAM File on remote hosts where you maintain access keys non-managed by SSHAM.</description></item></channel></rss>