<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About ssham on ssham: Secure Shell Access Manager</title><link>https://ssham.pacoorozco.info/about/</link><description>Recent content in About ssham on ssham: Secure Shell Access Manager</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ssham.pacoorozco.info/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Overview</title><link>https://ssham.pacoorozco.info/about/overview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssham.pacoorozco.info/about/overview/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Secure Shell, or Secure Socket Shell — commonly abbreviated as SSH — is a &lt;a
 class="gdoc-markdown__link"
 href="https://www.ssh.com/ssh/protocol/"
&gt;secure network protocol&lt;/a&gt; that allows users to securely authenticate to remote devices. SSH keys are used to access the &lt;a
 class="gdoc-markdown__link"
 href="https://www.ssh.com/ssh/protocol/"
&gt;SSH protocol&lt;/a&gt;. SSH leverages a pair of SSH keys to encrypt communication with a remote system. The key pair is cryptographic in nature and made up of a &lt;em&gt;public&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;private key&lt;/em&gt;. The keys work in tandem to provide authentication between the client and the remote system.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>SSH Authentication</title><link>https://ssham.pacoorozco.info/about/ssh-authentication/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssham.pacoorozco.info/about/ssh-authentication/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;SSH authentication is broadly categorized into two types: &lt;em&gt;password-based&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;public key authentication&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="flex align-center gdoc-page__anchorwrap"&gt;
 &lt;h2 id="1-password-based-authentication"
 &gt;
 1. Password-based authentication
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;a data-clipboard-text="https://ssham.pacoorozco.info/about/ssh-authentication/#1-password-based-authentication" class="gdoc-page__anchor clip flex align-center" title="Anchor to: 1. Password-based authentication" aria-label="Anchor to: 1. Password-based authentication" href="#1-password-based-authentication"&gt;
 &lt;svg class="gdoc-icon gdoc_link"&gt;&lt;use xlink:href="#gdoc_link"&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
 &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;password-based authentication&lt;/em&gt;, the client sends an authentication request to the server which includes the encrypted username and password for the remote server. Upon receipt, the server decrypts the request and validates the credentials in plain text. Once verified, the client is notified of the authentication outcome.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why ssham?</title><link>https://ssham.pacoorozco.info/about/why-ssham/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssham.pacoorozco.info/about/why-ssham/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Proper management over any type of resource and its access credentials enables a secure, well controlled environment. You can ensure proper protection of keys with &lt;strong&gt;SSH key management&lt;/strong&gt; — a combination of practices, policies, and tools for establishing secure SSH key usage routines within an organization. SSH key management can significantly enhance organization cybersecurity by protecting networks and systems from both external and insider attacks. It can also help an organization comply with cybersecurity standards, laws, and regulations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How it works</title><link>https://ssham.pacoorozco.info/about/how-it-works/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssham.pacoorozco.info/about/how-it-works/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;SSHAM runs on top of a bastion host. A bastion host is a server that has SSH access to other servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bastion host uses a SSH keypair to connect to the remote hosts. Every time that the bastion host wants to connect a remote server, it will use the private key. The remote server will authenticate the bastion host using the public key which was added the the remote&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;authorized_keys&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>